A Guide to the Records from the School Health Nurses, Arlington Public Schools, 1934-1991
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Records from the School Health Nurses, Arlington Public Schools, 1934-1991
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 169
16 boxes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Alethea Kolhonen, former School Nurse Supervisor, on May 8, 2007.
Historical Information
School health work began with Arlington's Public Health Department; tuberculosis, typhoid and diphtheria were the most pressing problems. An Arlington County Health Officer was appointed in 1923, and a public health nurse was assigned exclusively to the schools.
In 1939, the School Health Department came under the control of the Board of Education, and a full-time medical director was appointed. A Nursing Supervisor position was created in 1948. School nurses were transferred to the Department of Human Resources in 1973 and merged with Public Health nurses in 1983.
Scope and Content
The files of the School Health Nurses of Arlington Public Schools cover the time period from the 1950s to 1990, but include some as early as 1934 and some from the 1940s. During that time, School Nurses were moved from the jurisdiction of the Department of Education to the Department of Human Resources, and then merged with Public Health Nurses. The collection measures 6.7 linear feet.
Series 1 hold general administrative files, dealing with budgets, committees, staff meetings and school health history. The Staff Meeting files are comprehensive, from 1955 to 1979. Personnel files, including job descriptions, make up Series 2. Reports are in Series 3; of special interest are the School Narrative Reports, which the nurses wrote at the conclusion of each school year describing the conditions and events of that particular school. Most nurses covered more than one school. These reports cover the years from the mid-1950s to the late 1960s.
Series 4 contains files on medical information and nurses' education. It also includes many issues of publications of interest to school nurses, including Health Education and the Journal of School Health.
Series 5 deals specifically with the transfer of the School Nurses from the Department of Education to the Department of Human Resources in 1973, and then again the merger of School Nurses with Public Health Nurses in 1983. Series 6 are photographs.
Arrangement
The files arrived in various forms, some in file folders, some in binders, and some just loosely laid in boxes. Some were labeled, some were not. The files are arranged into six series by the archivist. The files were arranged in chronological and/or alphabetical order.
Two files contained floppy discs which are currently unread. They are in Series 3, Subseries 1, Files 17 and 18. The description on the floppy discs for File 17 reads "Nurses Reports, (FY 80)," and "'86 Statistics (Formatted 4/2/86)." "Nurses Worksheets FY-1987 (formatted 7/30/86)" is the label on File 18.
Series 6 are photographs, most of which were in envelopes with no identification. Each envelope was placed in a separate file and given a description by the archivist. Files with photographs outside of Series 6 have an asterisk [*] after the folder title.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
RG 7, Arlington County Public Schools
Related Material
RG 21, Records of the Arlington County Departments of Health
Index Terms
Subjects:
Arlington Public Schools (Arlington, Va.); Public schools -- United States.; Arlington Co., Va. Department of Health; Public health; Public health administration -- United States.; Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- School Nurse Administration
  - General Files
    - Arlington Health Services Association, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Arlington Paraprofessional Association, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Athletic Coaches' Handbook, Washington-Lee High School, Revised April 1982 (Box 1)
    - Civil Defense Committee, 1959-1964 (Box 1)
    - Clinic Aid Manual (Box 1)
    - Concepts of School Health Programs, Marjorie F. Hughes, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence between Marjorie Hughes, MD, Director, School Health Service, and Helen Hackman, MD, Chief, Division of Meidical Services, 1969-1972 (Box 1)
    - "A Decade of Progress, 1968-1978," Arlington County Department of Human Resources, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Departmental Performance Priority Standards, September 6, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Family Education Center for the Pregnant Teen (Box 1)
    - George Mason Advisory Board, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Gifted Students, 1962, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Goals for School Health Divisions, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Headstart Program, 1965-1969 (Box 1)
    - Health Services for School Children (Box 1)
    - Home Visit (Box 1)
    - Hospitality Committee, 1970-1985 (Box 1)
    - Overview of School Health Services, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
    - "Physical Education Standards of Learning Objectives, K-12," Draft [n.d.] (Box 1)
    - Pre-School Conferences, 1953-1963 (Box 1)
    - Pupil Personnel Services Certification, April 10, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Refugees, 1978-1981 (Box 1)
    - Retention of School Physician, March 26, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Role of School Nurses, 1971-1980 (Box 1)
    - School Entrance Requirements for Fall 1981, February 9, 1981 (Box 1)
    - School Health Video Outline [n.d.] (Box 1)
    - School Nursing Concerns, January 9, 1981 (Box 1)
    - "Secondary Program of Physical Education Intramurals and Intershcolastics," August 1977 (Box 1)
    - Standard Equipment & Supplies, Junior and Senior High Schools, December 29, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Vietnamese Students, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Indochinese Refugee Education Guides, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Your School Health Program, brochure [n.d.] (Box 2)
  - Budgets
    - Budget, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
    - Budget, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Budget Requests Filled, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
    - Budget, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - Budget Issue Slips, 1965-66 (Box 2)
    - Budget, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
    - Budget, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    - Budget Requests, September 1967 (Box 2)
    - Budget, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
    - Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
    - Budget, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - Budget, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Payroll, Examining Physicians, 1961-1971 (Box 2)
    - Payroll, Examining Physicians with Time Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - Payroll, Examininig Physicians with Time Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Payroll, Examining Physicians with Time Reports, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
    - Payroll, Examining Physicians with Time Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - Payroll, Examining Physicians with Time Reports, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Committees and Task Forces
    - Ad Hoc Committe for School Health Division, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on School Health Services, 1974 (Box 3)
    - Arlington County Board Advisory Committee on Health and Welfare, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
    - Arlington County Board Advisory Committee on Health and Welfare, Additional Materials, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
    - Employee Relations Committee, December 11, 1962 - May 17, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Employee Relations Committee, October 18, 1966 - May 21, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Employee Relations Committee, September 10, 1968 - April 18, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Principals' Handbook Committee, September 1960 (Box 3)
    - School Health Advisory Committee, 1951-1953 (Box 3)
    - School Health Advisory Committee, 1953-1956 (Box 4)
    - School Health Advisory Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Staff Council, 1965-1980 (Box 4)
    - Task Force for Review and Recommendations of Services for School-Age Children, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
    - Task Force to Study Clerical Staffing Patterns/Workloads, April 21, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Staff Meetings
    - Staff Meetings, September 12, 1955 - June 4, 1956 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 24, 1956 - May 10, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 26, 1957- June 24, 1958 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, September 2, 1958 - June 8, 1959 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 28, 1959 - June 8, 1960 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 22, 1960 - June 12, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 30, 1961 - June 4, 1962 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 21, 1962 - June 3, 1963 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 27, 1963 - June 30, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 26, 1964 - May 7, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 21, 1965 - June 30, 1966 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, September 12, 1966 - May 15, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 30, 1967 - June 5, 1968 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 30, 1968 - May 19, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Staff Meetings, August 28, 1969 - June 8, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Staff Meetings, August 26, 1970 - June 21, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Staff Meetings, September 1, 1971 - June 19, 1972 (Box 5)
    - Staff Meetings, August 30, 1972 - June 27, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Staff Meetings, July 13, 1973 - June 12, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Staff Meetings, August 29, 1974 - June 11, 1975 (Box 5)
    - Staff Meetings, August 28, 1975 - June 24, 1976 (Box 5)
    - Staff Meetings, August 31, 1976 - June 1, 1977 (Box 5)
    - Staff Meetings, August 31, 1977 - June 19, 1978 (Box 5)
    - Staff Meetings, August 29, 1978 - June 22, 1979 (Box 5)
  - School Health History
    - School Health Program, 1920-1948 (Box 5)
    - School Health Program, 1948-1955 (Box 5)
    - History of School Health, 1956-1972 (Box 5)
- Personnel
  - Job Descriptions
    - Assistant Supervisor of School Nurses [n.d.] (Box 5)
    - Generalized Public Health Nurses Protocol, Department of Health, State of Virginia, 1976 (Box 5)
    - Guidelines for School Nurses, Department of Education, Commonwealth of Virginia, August 1979 (Box 5)
    - Health Education Coordinator, May 15, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Nurse Aide, 1970, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Nurse's Aide Clinic Manual, Junior and Senior High Schools [n.d.] (Box 5)
    - Public Health Nurse-Related Class Titles, Virginia Department of Health Job Inventory, July, 1987 (Box 5)
    - School Health Supervisor (Box 5)
    - School Nurse, 1965-1991 (Box 5)
    - School Nurse Evaluation form, 1971 (Box 5)
    - School Nurse Specialist Packet, National Education Association, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Supervisor of School Health, February 6, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Orientation and Training
    - Blood Pressure Screening, Fun Fair, May 17, 1982 (Box 6)
    - Height, Weight and Vision Screenings, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Immunization Clinic Training, Draft II, June 1991 (Box 6)
    - Orientation - New School Health Nurses, July 20, 1982 (Box 6)
    - Red Cross Clinic, August 29, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Personnel Policies
    - Multiple-Grade Class Criteria, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Multiple-Grade Class Criteria, 1976-1978 (Box 6)
    - Multiple-Grade Class Criteria, 1979-1982 (Box 6)
    - Personnel Policies and Procedures, Arlington County Public Schools, Revised Edition, November 1958 (Box 6)
    - Personnel Policies and Salaries for Nurses and Dental Hygeienist, November 26, 1969 (Box 6)
    - State Personnel Rules, November 1977 (Box 6)
    - Snow Plans, December 26, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Salary and Insurance
    - 24 pay period for 10, 11, and 12 month "transferred" [n.d.] (Box 6)
    - Liability/Malpractice Insurance, 1975-1983 (Box 6)
    - Pay Plan, Arlington County, Fiscal 1973, 1980, 1981 (Box 6)
    - Pay Plan, Arlington County, Fiscal, 1982, 1984, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Salary Issues 1966-1988 (Box 6)
    - Salary Scales 1955-1969 (Box 6)
    - School Health Services Salary Study, March 1, 1972 (Box 6)
    - School Health Coverage Plan, 1985, June 15, 1984 (Box 6)
    - School Health Services, Staff Recommendations for Placement on Professional Pay Scale, May 10, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Virginia Supplemental Retirement System Employment Benefit Statements, January 14, 1975 - January 31, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Schedules
    - Nurse and Nurses' Aide Schedules, 1964-1989 (Box 7)
    - Substitutes for Health Services Staff, January 23, 1967 and January 27, 1967 (Box 7)
- Reports
  - Annual Reports
    - Annual Report, School Health Services, 1950-1954 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Services, 1954-1957 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Services, 1958-1961 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Services, 1961-1966 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Services, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Services, 1972-1975 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, Department of Human Resorces, Fiscal 1974 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Division, 1975-1976 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, Department of Human Resources, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Division, 1978-1979 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Division, 1979-1980 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Services Division, 1980-81 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Services, 1981-82 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Services, 1982-83 (Box 7)
    - Nurses' Annual Report, School Health Services, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
    - Nurses' Annual Report, School Health Services, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Services 1985-1986 [includes floppy disc] (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, School Health Services 1986-1987 [includes floppy disc] (Box 7)
    - Nurses Annual Report, School Health Services, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
    - Nurses Annual Report, Department of Human Services, 1988-1990 (Box 8)
    - Hearing Conservation Program, 1951-1953 (Box 8)
    - Hearing Conservation Program, 1953-1955 (Box 8)
    - Immunization Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Immunization Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 8)
    - Immunization Reports, 1981-1983 (Box 8)
    - Immunization Reports, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Other Reports
    - Absence Report for Schools, Monthly Averages, 1957-1966 (Box 8)
    - Case studies, 1954-1965 (Box 8)
    - Case Studies, [a day in], 1967 (Box 8)
    - Clinic Blueprints and Equipment [includes blueprints for Ashlawn and Thomas Jefferson schools] (Box 8)
    - Comparison of Nurse Days per 100 Pupils, January 9, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Dental Health Records, 1934-1941 (Box 8)
    - ESOL/HILT Statistics, 1987-1990; September 1990 (Box 8)
    - Family Center Report, 1984-1989 (Box 8)
    - Identification and Reporting of Handicapped Children, March 22, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Membership by Grades, 1964, 1966, and 1968 (Box 8)
    - Mid-Year Evaluation of 1970-1971 School Health Program (Box 8)
    - Nursing Hours Spent in School Health Programs, 1986-1988 (Box 8)
    - PHN Staff Turnover, December 9, 1983 (Box 8)
    - School Health Data for Special Education Report, January 8, 1973 (Box 8)
    - School Health Floods, 1981-1983; December 22, 1983 (Box 8)
    - School Health Survey, July 1, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Sight-Saving Class, August 30, 1957 (Box 8)
    - Survey of Competitive Sports Candidates, May 1986 (Box 8)
  - School Narrative Reports
    - Abingdon Elementary School, 1957-1966; 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Ashlawn Elementary School, 1956-1975 (Box 9)
    - Barcroft Elementary School, 1965-1975 (Box 9)
    - Barrett School, 1956-1966; 1986 (Box 9)
    - Brandon School, July 29, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Cherrydale, 1954-1963 (Box 9)
    - Claremont Elementary School, 1956-1965 (Box 9)
    - Clay and Fillmore Elementary Schools 1954-1963 (Box 9)
    - Custis Elementary School, 1956-1967 (Box 9)
    - Drew-Kemper School, 1956-1966; 1986 (Box 9)
    - Edison School, 1949-1967 (Box 9)
    - Fairlington Elementary School, 1954-1966 (Box 9)
    - Fort Meyer, Spring 1968 (Box 9)
    - Glencarlyn Elementary School, 1958-1966; 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Gunston Junior High School, 1958-1970 (Box 9)
    - Hoffman-Boston Elementary School, 1954-1967 (Box 9)
    - Hoffman-Boston Junior and Senior High School, 1954-1956 (Box 9)
    - Jackson School, June 15, 1965 (Box 9)
    - Jamestown Elementary School, 1956-1966; 1974-1975 * (Box 9)
    - Kenmore Junior High School, 1956-1966; 1973-1975 (Box 9)
    - Key School, 1971-1975 (Box 9)
    - Langston Elementary School, 1959-1966 (Box 9)
    - Lee-Reed School, 1965-1967 (Box 9)
    - Long Branch School [n.d.] (Box 9)
    - Madison Elementary School, 1955-1968 (Box 9)
    - Marshall Annex [n.d.] (Box 9)
    - Maury Elementary School, 1955-1966; 1970 (Box 9)
    - McKinley Elementary School, 1956-1967; 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Monroe School, 1955-1968 (Box 9)
    - Nottingham Elementary School, 1956-1966; 1971-1975 (Box 9)
    - Oakridge Elementary School, 1956-1967 (Box 9)
    - Page School, 1956-1966 (Box 9)
    - Patrick Henry School, 1956-1967; 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Randolph Elementary School, 1956-1967; 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Robert E. Lee Elementary School, 1956-1963 (Box 9)
    - Stewart School, 1956-1962 (Box 9)
    - Stratford Junior High School 1959-1962 (Box 9)
    - Swanson Junior High School, 1956-1967; 1989-1990 (Box 9)
    - Taylor Elementary School, 1956-1967 (Box 9)
    - Thomas Jefferson Junior High School, 1954-1972; 1990 (Box 9)
    - Tuckahoe Elementary School, 1956-1966; 1974-1978 (Box 9)
    - Wakefield High School, 1956-1966; 1974-1975; 1989-1990 (Box 9)
    - Walter Reed School, 1953-1966 (Box 9)
    - Washington-Lee High School, 1956-1967; 1978; 1989-1990 (Box 9)
    - Williamsburg Junior High School, 1954-1966 * (Box 10)
    - Wilson School, 1955-1968 (Box 10)
    - Woodlawn School, 1954-1966 (Box 10)
    - Woodmont School, 1954-1966 (Box 10)
    - Yorktown High School, 1956-1966; 1974-1975 (Box 10)
- Medical Information
  - General Medical Information
    - Chiropractic (Virginia State Code), 1956; 1960 (Box 10)
    - Christian Science, 1949-1961 (Box 10)
    - Color Vision Testing, 1960-1961 (Box 10)
    - Diagrammatic Drawing of a Thermometer (Box 10)
    - Drug Abuse, 1970-1980 (Box 10)
    - Drug Interactions, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Food Clippings [magazine clippings of various food items] (Box 10)
    - Head Lice, 1987-1991 (Box 10)
    - Health Education Materials, 1969-1972 (Box 10)
    - Health Education Materials, 1969-1972 (Box 10)
    - Lactose and Milk Intolerance, 1972, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Mental Health, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Nutrition, 1973-1979 (Box 10)
    - Parasite Instinal, 1975-1980 (Box 10)
    - Pavovirus B19 (Fifth Disease), 1989-1990 (Box 10)
    - Prepackaged School Lunch, April 15, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Scoliosis, 1976-1978 (Box 10)
    - Sex Education (Box 10)
  - Virginia Education Association, Department of School Nurses
    - Constitutions, 1964-1972 (Box 10)
    - Directories 1969-1973 (Box 10)
    - Meetings, 1964-1969 (Box 11)
    - Meetings, 1970-1974 (Box 11)
    - Publications (Box 11)
  - Conferences
    - Arlington Council on Health and Medical Care, April 19, 1949 (Box 11)
    - Arlington Management Institute [1989] (Box 11)
    - Association for the Advancement of Health Education, December, 1978 (Box 11)
    - Committee on Certification of School Nurses of the Department of School Nurses of the Virginia Education Association, September 11, 1971 (Box 11)
    - Conference Notes (Box 11)
    - Conference of School Nurses August 6-8, 1986 (Box 11)
    - Department of Public Health, Government of the District of Columbia, Workshop for Secondary School Nurses, June 17-28, 1968 (Box 11)
    - Drug Abuse Seminar, December 1980 (Box 11)
    - "Footwork - During the Q & A," September 27-28,1977 (Box 11)
    - School Nurses Conference, September 27-28, 1977 (Box 11)
    - Self-Medication: The New Era, Symposium, March 31, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Nurse Education
    - School Nurse Achievement Program, Self-Instruction Module #1: Introduction to the Nursing Process, [n.d.] (Box 11)
    - School Nurse Achievement Program, Self-Instruction Module #2: Growth and Development, by Judith B. Igoe, [n.d.] (Box 11)
    - School Nurse Achievement Program, Self-Instruction Module #3: Dealing with Emotional Disorders, by Jon Esty, [n.d.] (Box 11)
    - School Nurse Achievement Program, Self-Instruction Module #4: Dealing with Chronic Illness, by Jan McNally, [n.d.] (Box 11)
    - School Nurse Achievement Program, Self-Instruction Module #5: Dealing with Physical Handicaps, by Carol Grunfeld, [n.d.] (Box 11)
    - School Nurse Achievement Program, Self-Instruction Module #6: Specific Learning Disabilities, by Judith B. Igoe, [n.d.] (Box 11)
    - School Nurse Achievement Program, Self-Instruction Module #7: Mental Retardation, by Patricia A. Motz, [n.d.] (Box 11)
    - School Nurse Achievement Program, Team Assessment Exercise, [n.d.] (Box 11)
  - Publications
    - "Aspirin and Acetaminophen," Symposia Reporter, August 1978 (Box 12)
    - The American Nurse, January 1980 and June 1985 (Box 12)
    - Analysis of School Nurse Program, North Syracuse Central School District, February 1964 (Box 12)
    - "Essential Nursing Services to Meet the Health Needs of Students in Public Schools," State Department of Health, 1974 (Box 12)
    - An Evaluation Guide for School Nursing Practice, Designed for Self and Peer Review, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Family Planning Perspectives, July 1982 (Box 12)
    - "Functions and Qualifications for School Nurses," The American Nurses' Association, 1961 and 1966 (Box 12)
    - "A Guide for Teaching Poison Prevention in Kindergartens and Primary Grades," U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, Washington, DC, May 1972 (Box 12)
    - Guidelines for School Nurses, August 1979 (Box 12)
    - Health Education, July-August 1976 and January-February 1977 (Box 12)
    - Health Education, September-October 1977 and November-December 1977 (Box 12)
    - Health Education, January-February 1978, September-October 1979, and January-February 1980 (Box 12)
    - "Health Manual for Schools," Department of Education, Commmonwealth of Virginia, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Health Values, July-August 1977, November-December 1977, and January-February 1979 (Box 12)
    - "Individualized and Prescriptive School Nursing Services for Students in the Physically Handicapped Regular Day Class Program," 1976 (Box 12)
    - The Journal of School Health, September 1963 and June 1964 (Box 12)
    - The Journal of School Health, December 1964 and June 1966 (Box 12)
    - The Journal of School Health, February 1967 and May 1969 (Box 13)
    - The Journal of School Health, October 1976 and March 1978 (Box 13)
    - The Journal of School Health, October 1976 and March 1978 (Box 13)
    - The Journal of School Health, September 1978 and October 1978 (Box 13)
    - The Journal of School Health, January 1979 and February 1979 (Box 13)
    - The Journal of School Health, March 1979 and October 1979 (Box 13)
    - Journal of School Health, March 1980, April 1980, and October 1984 (Box 13)
    - Journal of School Health, September 1990 (Box 13)
    - The Journal of School Nursing, September 1990 (Box 13)
    - Maternal Health Care Cenres of the City of Helsinki, 1948-1960 (Box 13)
    - National Association of School Nurses (Box 13)
    - "Practice Oriented Theory: Part 1," in Advances in Nursing Science, October 1978 (Box 13)
    - School Health Review, July/August 1973 (Box 13)
    - School Nurse Specialist Packet (Box 14)
    - School Nurse/Teacher, The University of the State of New York, File 1 (Box 14)
    - School Nurse/Teacher, The University of the State of New York, File 2 (Box 14)
    - SNT Reporter, Spring 1976 (Box 14)
    - "Standards: Community Health Nursing Practice and Psychiatric-Mental Health Nursing Practice," American Nurses' Association, 1973 (Box 14)
    - "Standards of School Nursing Practice," American Nurses' Association, 1983 (Box 14)
    - "Stress," American Journal of Nursing, November 1979 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, File 1 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, File 2 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 14)
- Transfer of School Nurses from the Department of Education to Department of Human Resources
  - School Health Services Transfer to County Health Program, 1963 1963-1970 (Box 14)